ALYS COOPER

About Me

Full-stack software engineer leveraging over ten years of marketing and client-facing experience to write user-first applications that keep in mind both internal and external stakeholders. I specialize in connecting with people of all knowledge levels and backgrounds while unraveling complex concepts in straightforward, transparent, and relatable ways.

Skills

JavaScript, React.js, JQuery, Python, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Bootstrap, Heroku, Express, Node.js, SQL (PostgreSQL), NoSQL (MongoDB), Git/GitHub, Zapier, Microsoft Excel, Photoshop, Canva, Agile Workflow, Jira, TypeScript, Project Management

Software Development Projects

MARCH 2022 - PRESENT

MyJunimoApp - Full-stack inventory and crafting management app for the video game Stardew Valley.

- Built using the Django-React stack within a week while collaborating with a front-end developer colleague, handling the development to launch process using daily SCRUM meetings and Agile planning approach.
- Created scalable back-end infrastructure for front-end fetch calls, with plenty of room for feature expansion.
- Used Postgres SQL architecture to create multiple interrelated tables (particularly in regards to inventory and blueprint required materials).

Freelancr - Full-stack application that allows freelancers to connect with and advertise to consumers.

- Led the development team as Project Manager in an week-long Agile/Scrum development cycle to manage deadlines, code implementation, and QA.
- Utilized MERN to build a full stack application, with full CRUD operations hitting all RESTful API calls.
- Fully integrated with Stripe API to allow credit card purchases for services.
- Created responsive front-end with React and ReactBootstrap to ensure consistency in the viewing experience for all devices.

PracticeHelper - Full-stack application that simplifies tracking music practice statistics for musicians of all stripes.

- Utilized MongoDB, Express, & Node.js to build a full stack application, with full create, read, update, delete (CRUD)
 operations hitting all RESTful API calls.
- Made RESTful API fetch calls with Open Opus Classical Music API to an Express, MongoDB, Node.js backend handling to assist with create, read, update, delete (CRUD) operations, and tested all backend routes during development using Postman.
- Used Mongoose to define schemas for MongoDB collections on the Back-end.
- Implemented responsive Liquid layouts for user-facing pages with CSS3 and Bootstrap.

Counting Sheep - Front-End Browser-Based, Corgi-Centric Sheep Herding Simulator Application.

- Used HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript languages to create playable browser game with timer, persistent scoreboard, life/health systems, and win conditions.
- Designed, wireframed and planned UI design of application using Miro whiteboard tools.

Professional Experience

TRBO ADvance, LLC - Director, Digital Media Buy

MARCH 2021 - JANUARY 2022

- Led global team's digital marketing efforts including automation, strategy, operations, and communications using Agile (Scrum) principles at both the product and operations level.
- Utilized synchronous & asynchronous communication skills/methods to keep team members aligned on weekly deliverables.
- Assisted in securing our biggest new client (\$100k monthly budget) with a bold new marketing strategy, initial
 marketing launch, and data analysis.

MD Connect, Inc. - Digital Marketing Manager

MARCH 2018 - FEBRUARY 2021

- Oversaw paid social media marketing for our largest client, managing \$2 million in marketing spend over the last year
 which included paused operations in March-April 2020.
- Managed data analytics and reported weekly directly to the CMO about our performance to forecast.
- Collaborated closely with the client's creative agency to turn available performance data for each creative into future plans to capitalize on "winning" creative and messaging.

Web.com Agency Services - Social Media Specialist, Tier III

FEBRUARY 2013 - OCTOBER 2017

- Created, scheduled, and budgeted monthly individual Facebook and Instagram campaigns for ~20 clients ranging from the \$100-\$5,000 budget range.
- Collaborated with leadership to create quality metrics for the team, based on KPL performance, customer satisfaction, and productivity, and implemented those in new training documentation.

Education

General Assembly

Software Engineering Immersive

University of North Florida

BA in English and Spanish